How AI fits?
You can use AI to validate or generate
interview questions. Um, you should make
sure that you are following all of the
rules, but you can simulate also
interview scenarios, especially at the
beginning. You can discover what you can
expect in interview scenarios more than
I can tell you, but it is unexpected.
You might meet people that are super
talkative that will tell you everything
and you'll be so amazed about what you
discovered. And you might meet people
that
don't say anything. Uh, you can
structure the interview notes. Of
course, you can use many tools for for
that, but yeah. Uh, and you can extract
patterns from multiple interviews and
see what's common, but guess what? Your
mind already will do that. So, if you
are in all those interviews, you will
already have the patterns, the insights,
and so on. Because talking to users,
um, when done right with the right right
questions, um,
it's amazing how many things, uh, you
you find out.
So, with AI, you prepare and analyze.
You don't replace the talking to users.
You shouldn't validate your idea with AI
because not AI will use your product,
but people, users.
Uh, and you shouldn't decide what users
need without talking to users and
validating a need with users because AI
is kind of fiction.
Um, a prompt
you should, yeah, be a UX researcher,
um, or you can also be a product manager
in this, uh, situation. You can generate
open-ended questions. You can put in all
of the information I put around this or
generate another prompt that is much
longer that would give you better, uh,
results.
Um, and, uh, yeah. Here, like, focus on,
uh, behavior. shouldn't do leading
questions. You can tell them to use
you can tell them to use the Mom Test
book and insights. And yeah, you should
not ask for opinions. I just put here
some things that are important to
mention.